<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lessons</title>
    <link>/data-curation/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lessons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>STRI-CON</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/data-curation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesson 1: Building Your Working 🧱️ Environment</title>
      <link>/data-curation/2020/04/01/lesson-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/2020/04/01/lesson-1/</guid>
      <description>We have a wide range of experience levels in this course, so the first lesson is devoted to setting up your working environment and laying down a good foundation for your projects. I would like to give everyone a chance to get everything installed and to get comfortable with these new tools before we dive in. I realize that some of you may have a lot of this done already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorials</title>
      <link>/data-curation/page/tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/page/tutorials/</guid>
      <description>As advertised, this course is about using R Markdown and GitHub. I appreciate that some of you may not want to spend time learning new skills that you probably won&amp;rsquo;t use. I decided to make this Tutorials page with optional material for anyone who wants to expand their knowledge beyond the immediate goals of the course.
HTML &amp;amp; CSS Websites are built on HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. For any site, HTML defines the content and structure; CSS provides the style and layout; JavaScript programs the behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Open Science</title>
      <link>/data-curation/2020/03/31/rationale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/2020/03/31/rationale/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to share a few thoughts on what I see as key benefits to the community in creating data driven, open source, web products that capture and communicate your science. Bear with me for a minute. Well technically 4 minutes.
Accessibility &amp;amp; Inclusivity Many journals and journal articles sit behind pay walls that a lot of people can’t access. That sucks, and while people are revolting against this paradigm, for now this is the reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Course</title>
      <link>/data-curation/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Estimated reading time: 5 minutes, 12 seconds.
Welcome Welcome to the LockDown 2020 Continuing Education course on Data Curation. This site (written mainly in R Markdown) will be our guidebook as we make our way through the topics. Our main goals with the course are to a) create interactive, data-driven web products in R Markdown, b) host those products on GitHub, and c) use tools like figshare for hosting data and data products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesson 0: An Example R Markdown Document</title>
      <link>/data-curation/2020/03/28/lesson-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/2020/03/28/lesson-0/</guid>
      <description>In this mini lesson I’d like to demonstrate a) some Markdown syntax, b) how you run and format R code, and c) how to render R figures. If you read the Course Description you have already seen examples of embedded tables. Remember, our primary goal is to create R Markdown documents that capture code, data, and data products.
 R Markdown integrates the concepts of literate programming and reproducible research, which, in addition to explaining or documenting itself, also allows others (including an original investigator) to reproduce a data analysis or other research result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/data-curation/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>Coming Soon We (you and I) will add tools to this page as we go along. Until then, here&amp;rsquo;s a puppy.
  puppy   Photo credit Dog789, licenced under CC BY-SA. Original file.
 Edit this page  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>