<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Markdown on Lessons &amp; Readings</title>
    <link>/data-curation/tags/r-markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R Markdown on Lessons &amp; Readings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>STRI-CON</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/data-curation/tags/r-markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Exercises</title>
      <link>/data-curation/2020/05/01/practicals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/2020/05/01/practicals/</guid>
      <description>This page provides quick links to the Practical Exercises—the hands-on learning portion of the course. These exercises are written entirely in R Markdown, as opposed to the course website, which contains Hugo, CSS, and HTML code. Because I want you to work in pure R Markdown, I created separate pages for the exercises. The look and feel of these pages are different than the main course website. What this means is that you should be able to implement anything you see on the Practical Pages in your own documents using only R Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesson 2: Single Page R Markdown 📃 Document</title>
      <link>/data-curation/2020/04/21/lesson-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/2020/04/21/lesson-2/</guid>
      <description>Here is the link to the Practicals Page for Lesson 2. I will add new assignments every day or so to help you create a single page document. For now you can find the raw .Rmd file on GitHub. The link is in the title of the Practicals Page.  R Markdown is a versatile framework for creating a range of high-quality documents including HTML, PDF, presentations, books, websites, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Topics</title>
      <link>/data-curation/page/topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/page/topics/</guid>
      <description> This page contains an outline of topics we will cover in this course and will updated often. As always, suggestions are welcome.   Please continue to work on your skills in CSS, HTML, and CLI. See the Self-Paced Tutorials for more information.
   Lesson Topic Skills     L0 R Markdown example    L1 Setup IDE, Dev Tools, GitHub, RStudio   L1 Problem Solving Web search, GitHub, StackOverflow   L2 R Markdown Page YAML, Markdown, R Code chunks, inline R Code   L2 R Markdown Page Tables, Figures   L3 GitHub Submitting Issues &amp;amp; Requests, Pull Requests   L3 Git &amp;amp; GitHub Git from the CLI, Creating &amp;amp; cloning a Repo, Push changes   L4 Customization CSS style sheets, inline HTML code   L4 R Markdown Site Take what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned and make a site    Archiving Data Figshare      Edit this page  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesson 0: An Example R Markdown Document</title>
      <link>/data-curation/2020/03/28/lesson-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/2020/03/28/lesson-0/</guid>
      <description>In this mini lesson I’d like to demonstrate a) some Markdown syntax, b) how you run and format R code, and c) how to render R figures. If you read the Course Description you have already seen examples of embedded tables. Remember, our primary goal is to create R Markdown documents that capture code, data, and data products.
 R Markdown integrates the concepts of literate programming and reproducible research, which, in addition to explaining or documenting itself, also allows others (including an original investigator) to reproduce a data analysis or other research result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/data-curation/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>This page is a work in progress and will be updated on the fly.
 Pictoral Table of Contents.  R Markdown  R Markdown: The Definitive Guide. Title says it all. You should use this. A lot.
  R Markdown Cookbook. Another must have. RStudio IDE Cheatsheet. An overview of the RStudio IDE. R Markdown Cheatsheet. A general R Markdown reference. Another R Markdown Cheatsheet. One more? There are a lot of cheatsheets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>