<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Lessons &amp; Readings</title>
    <link>/data-curation/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Lessons &amp; Readings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>STRI-CON</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/data-curation/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Page</title>
      <link>/data-curation/page/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/page/testing/</guid>
      <description>Nothing to see here. This is for testing only. I should use a different GH branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Topics</title>
      <link>/data-curation/page/topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/page/topics/</guid>
      <description> This page contains an outline of topics we will cover in this course and will updated often. As always, suggestions are welcome.   Please continue to work on your skills in CSS, HTML, and CLI. See the Self-Paced Tutorials for more information.
   Lesson Topic Skills     L0 R Markdown example    L1 Setup IDE, Dev Tools, GitHub, RStudio   L1 Problem Solving Web search, GitHub, StackOverflow   L2 R Markdown Page YAML, Markdown, R Code chunks, inline R Code    R Markdown Page Tables, Figures    GitHub Submitting Issues &amp;amp; Requests, Pull Requests    Git &amp;amp; GitHub Git from the CLI, Creating &amp;amp; cloning a Repo, Push changes    Customization CSS style sheets, inline HTML code    R Markdown Site Take what you&amp;rsquo;ve learned and make a site    Archiving Data Figshare      Edit this page  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Paced Tutorials</title>
      <link>/data-curation/page/tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/page/tutorials/</guid>
      <description>Jump to: CLI tutorials, HTML/CSS Tutorials.
 As advertised, this course is about using R Markdown and GitHub. I appreciate that some of you may not want to spend time learning new skills that you don&amp;rsquo;t think you need. Originally I considered everything on this page to be optional, however I changed my mind. As I thought more about the structure of the course, I concluded that I would be doing you all a disservice if I made tools like HTML and CSS optional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Course</title>
      <link>/data-curation/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Estimated reading time: 5 minutes, 12 seconds.
Welcome Welcome to the LockDown 2020 Continuing Education course on Data Curation. This site (written mainly in R Markdown) will be our guidebook as we make our way through the topics. Our main goals with the course are to a) create interactive, data-driven web products in R Markdown, b) host those products on GitHub, and c) use tools like figshare for hosting data and data products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/data-curation/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-curation/page/resources/</guid>
      <description>This page contains quick access to valuable resources, categorized by language or tool including R Markdown, YAML, Markdown, Command Line Interface, CSS &amp;amp; HTML, MathJax.   General Learn X in Y minutes. Where X is a programming language. Tutorials available English, Spanish, and many other languages. Use the Highlight your language: button in the upper right corner to filter. Tutorials includes:
 R English (EN), R Espanol (ES). Markdown EN, Markdown ES.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>